Harold Christy Schwalen papers, 1896-1967 (bulk 1919-1965)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Subgroup IV: Surface and Groundwater Studies
  The Department carried out the first quantitative study of a water supply in the Rillito portion of the Santa Cruz Valley in 1910, which was widely read throughout irrigated countries. The study revealed sources, movements, extent, and limitations of groundwater, and indicated how the groundwater should be obtained, as from a basin rather than an underflow, and determined the economics of groundwater utilization. Since that time, groundwater studies were carried out in seven other Arizona Valleys. These were not as extensive because of facts established by the Rillito study, but did serve as a basis for irrigation development.
  - Series XVII: Casa Grande Valley, 1917-1921
    Groundwater studies in Casa Grande Valley were a continuation of the work crried out in the Rillito Valley in 1910.
    - Effect of pumping groundwater. 1917 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Groundwater fluctuations. 1915-1919 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Historical data. 1941 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Pumping plant test data. 1915-1920 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Pumping plant test data. 1930-1931 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Water supply and irrigation report. 1921 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Well curb elevations. 1915 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Well water level measurements, Casa Grande/Maricopa. 1947 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Well records, notes on discharge, logs. 1914-1915 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Well locations. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Series XVIII: Little Chino Valley/Chino Valley, 1906-1967
    The Agriculture Engineering Dept. initiated groundwater studies in Little Chino Valley in the fall of 1937, continuing 2 weeks of field work/year until 1967. In common with other areas in Arizona that are wholly dependent on groundwater for irrigation water supply, Little Chino Valley artesian area had been developed beyond its natural rate of recharge. The results of the studies and their interpretation are essential to the understanding and solution to the water supply problem in the Valley. Researchers accumulated well drilling information and well logs, spring water and artesian pressure measurements, established benchmark elevations at well locations, measured well discharge, carried out crop surveys for establishing groundwater use, and accumulated geohydrologic information in the groundwater basin.
    - Annual report computations. 1960 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Artesian pressures and water levels. 1935-1951 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Chemical analysis of wells. 1952 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Consumptive use, notes and charts. 1941-1953 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence. 1942-1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Land use maps. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Maps. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Power consumption Tapco, Prescott. 1942-1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Pump test data. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Rainfall records. 1866-1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Reactance values. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Report on Chino Valley project. 1946 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Seasonal fluctuations. 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Summary crop reports. 1962 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Water analysis. 1937-1957 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Water spreading and reseeding project. 1939 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Well and pump data. 1938-1950 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Well elevations. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Bagdad Copper Co., groundwater development, correspondence and notes. 1937 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Bagdad Copper Co., groundwater development, maps. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Del Rio Springs, flow records. 1939-1946 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Del Rio Springs, groundwater profile. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Del Rio Springs, Wier readings. 1937-1962 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Pollock ranch well data. 1942 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Prescott, correspondence. 1942-1969 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Prescott, field notes. 1952-1954 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Prescott, well logs. 1940-1949 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Veterans' Administration, water supply developments. 1943-1944 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Series IXX: San Pedro River Valley, 1914-1962
    Box 17 contains records of area water studies, many of which were made to determine what effect a storage dam at Charleston would have on the flow of the San Pedro River waters. (See Box 51 for charts, 1928-1940). Box 18 contains results of studies on transpiration of grasses and trees as they relate to well water levels. Recorders for the studies are in boxes 51 and 52.
    - Benson, Canal gage books. 1925-1927 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Benson, heading dam sketch. 1921 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cascabel, Groundwater supply. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Charleston dam, clippings. 1914-1963 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Charleston dam, correspondence. 1963 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Charleston dam, maps and charts. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Charleston dam, studies. 1920-1942 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Discharge records, Babocomari. 1921-1925 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Discharge records, Charleston. 1945-1959 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Discharge records, Fairbanks. 1918-1920 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Discharge records, Hereford. 1919-1921 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Discharge records, Mexican border to Gila. 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Discharge records, Mexican border to Gila, summary reports. 1921-1922 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Discharge records, Miscellaneous records. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Discharge records, Redington. 1943-1962 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Discharge records, St. David Canal. 1921-1927 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Discharge records, Winkleman. 1927 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Discharge records, Winkleman gage books. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - St. David, canal. 1921-1927 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - St. David, correspondence. 1926-1933 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - St. David, Diversion dam, H.B. #86. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - St. David, Diversion dam, maps and charts. (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - St. David, Diversion dam, reports. 1926-1933 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - San Pedro Valley, correspondence. 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - San Pedro Valley, history. (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - San Pedro Valley, low water flow. 1922-1927 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - San Pedro Valley, maps. (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - San Pedro Valley, soil analysis, Upper San Pedro. 1922-1923 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - San Pedro Valley, water analysis. 1920 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - San Pedro Valley, well lists. (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - San Pedro Valley, wells and pump irrigation data. 1949-1950 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Mesquite/Cottonwood wells (Redington), correspondence. 1921-1922 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Mesquite/Cottonwood wells (Redington), notes and charts. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Mesquite/Cottonwood wells (Redington), temperature records. 1922-1923 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Sacaton well, correspondence. 1922-1925 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Sacaton well, notes and charts. 1923 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Salt Grass Well (Wilcox), correspondence. 1920-1925 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Salt Grass Well (Wilcox), notes and well data. 1923 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Transpiration in trees. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Series XX: San Simon Valley, 1914-1921
    Series deals with the drilling of a 2000' artesian and water supply test well in the San Simon Valley, Cochise County.
    - San Simon Deep Well, correspondence. 1922-1926 (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
    - San Simon Deep Well, history. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - San Simon Deep Well, proposal. 1920 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - San Simon Deep Well, well log. 1924 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - San Simon Deep Well, driller's reports, 0-1370' and 1370-2000'. (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
    - San Simon Valley, clippings. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - San Simon Valley, maps. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - San Simon Valley, photographs. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - San Simon Valley, rainfall report. 1921 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - San Simon Valley, rainfall report notes. 1921 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - San Simon Valley, runoff. 1920 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Series XXI: Sulphur Springs Valley, 1916-1940
    - Annual irrigation report. 1926 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Maps, charts. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Well and pump irrigation data. 1916-1940 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Series XXII: Santa Cruz Valley, Tucson area, 1903-1967
    One box of material contains numerous studies on Tucson's water supply. A second box of material contains information on the various committees formed to deal with water problems in the Tucson area. See also Flow/discharge records, boxes 34, 35, and 36.
    - Discharge/runoff of Tucson area rivers. 1903- (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Diversion channel. 1964 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Drilling log, well SC #15. 1963 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Flood runoff study. 1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Geophysical reports. 1964 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Gravity survey. (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Groundwater countour map. 1939 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Groundwater recharge. 1945 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Rainfall runoff. (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Water analysis for City of Tucson. 1952-1964 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Water analysis for Tucson area. 1944-1962 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Water development studies. 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Water development studies, invoices. (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Water development studies, maps and specs. (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Water supply and population statistics. 1920-1940 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Water supply estimates. 1913 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Water supply estimates. 1930 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Water supply estimates. 1960-2030 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Water supply system report by G.E.P. Smith. 1913 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Water supply system letters and reports. 1913- (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Flowing Wells Irrigation District, maps and charts. (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Flowing Wells Irrigation District, reports and studies. 1930-1947 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Flowing Wells Irrigation District, well data. 1932-1941 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Ad hoc committee on Tucson water supply. 1962 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Citizens' water committee, correspondence. 1950-1951 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Citizens' water committee, correspondence. 1953-1955 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Citizens' water committee, minutes and reports. 1951-1953 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - City council, planning study on well development. 1961 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Groundwater consulting board, contract. 1964 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Groundwater consulting board, maps and charts. 1964 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Groundwater consulting board, minutes. 1964-1967 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Groundwater consulting board, reports. 1964 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Groundwater consulting board, well cost. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Metropolitan water & sanitary committee, correspondence. 1967 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Metropolitan water & sanitary committee, minutes. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Rillito Creek Hydroligic Committee. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Tucson area water supply committee. 1923-1932 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - U.S. Bureau of Relcamation Project. 1968 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Water Advisory Board, minutes. 1964-1968 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Water Advisory Board, organization. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Water bonds. 1949-1963 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Water supply seminar. (Box 21, Folder 19)
- Subgroup V: Water Resource Studies
  - Series XXIII: Wells and Pump Irrigation Data
    Well logs provide information for interpretation of the geohydrologic character of an area, and the Department made every effort to get the most complete collection possible. Series contains information on wells throughout Arizona. These are needed in any study of underground waters in addition to being valuable to individual owners of wells. See also photographs, many of which are organized by township and range.
    - Wells and pump irrigation, contains data collected on wells throughout the state and includes elevation, depth of well, quality of water, and name of driller. 1906-1946 (Box 22)
    - Wells and pump irrigation, contains data collected on wells throughout the state and includes elevation, depth of well, quality of water, and name of driller. 1906-1946 (Box 23)
    - Arizona represntative wells, T10-19S/R12-14E. 1940-1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Historic wells. 1914-1930 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Irrigation power rates. 1943-1949 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Irriatio power rates. 1952-1961 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Wells and pump irrigation reports. 1926-1939, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Specifications for drilling test well. 1931 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - T11-14N/R26-28E (Lyman Dam area). 1939 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Cochise County well logs, Well measurements report. 1946-1947 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - T11-12S/R24-31E (Bowie). 1915- (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - San Simon Valley well logs, Artesian well data. 1919 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - San Simon Valley well logs, not located. 1911- (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - San Simon Valley well logs, Bear Springs Oil & Gas. 1930 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - T12S/R29E (San Simon Valley). (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - T13S/R28-29E (San Simon Valley). 1919- (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - T13S/R30-31E (San Simon Valley). 1919- (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - T14S/R25-31E (San Simon Valley). 1913- (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - T15S/R31-32E (San Simon Valley). 1919- (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - T13S/R19-24E (Willcox). 1921-1936 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - T15S/R21-25E (Willcox). 1915- (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - T16S/R23-25E (Willcox). 1911- (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - State Test Well (Willcox). (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - T17S/R19-25E (Benson/St. David). 1911-1921 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - T18S/R21E (Benson/St. David). 1921 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - T18S/R21E (Benson/St. David). 1921 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - T19S/R20-26E (Tombstone area). 1912- (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - T20S/R20-27E (McNeal). 1914 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Cochise County well logs, T21-22S/R20E (Ft. Huachuca). 1931- (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Cochise County well logs, T21S/R23-26E (McNeal). 1912- (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Cochise County well logs, T22S/R26E (Douglas). 1911 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Cochise County well logs, T23-24S/R21-22E. 1921-1922 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Cochise County well logs, T24S/R23-27E (Douglas/Bisbee). 1920- (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Coconino County well logs, T41M/R6W (Cone Beds). 1937 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Gila County well logs, not located. 1917- (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Gila County well logs, Miami-Globe area. 1913 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Graham County well logs, T5-11S/R22-27E (Fort Grant). 1916 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Graham County well logs, Fort Grant Damsite correspondence and reports. 1930-1950 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Greenlee County well logs, T4S/R30E (Clifton). 1942 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T1S (Phoenix area). 1929 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T1N (Phoenix area). 1925 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T1N/R3E (Arizona State Hospital). 1950 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T1N/R5E (Mesa Experiment Farm). 1954 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T1N/R4E (Salt River Valley Citrus Farm). 1945 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T3N-7N/R1-5W (Gila Bend). 1912 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T2S/R5E (Southwest Cotton Co.). 1926 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T2S/R6-7E (Chandler Heights). 1939 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T3-6S/R4-6W (Gila Bend area). 1923- (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Maricopa County well logs, T5S/R9W (Sentinel Dam). 1922- (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Pima County well logs, Arizona Public Service Co. 1953 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Pima County well logs, Continental. 1917 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Pima County well logs, Esmond, Pantano. 1907 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Pima County well logs, Flowing Wells. 1931-1934 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Pima County well logs, Santa Cruz River south of Tucson. 1922-1930 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Pima County well logs, Silverbell. 1955 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Pima County well logs, Tucson wells (not located) A-E. 1934- (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Pima County well logs, 8 Tucson wells (not located) F-L. 1934- (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Pima County well logs, Tucson wells (not located) M-R. 1934- (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Pima County well logs, Tucson wells (not located) S-Z. 1934- (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Pima County well logs, Water levels by McCash. 1930- (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Pima County well logs, T11S/R1E, (Tucson). 1918 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Pima County well logs, T11S/R8-11E. 1948 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Pima County well logs, T12S/R3,6,8E. 1948 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Pima County well logs, T12S/R12E (Hardin well). 1939 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Pima County well logs, T13S/R3,7E. 1949 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Pima County well logs, T13S/R13E (City of Tucson test well). 1966 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Pima County well logs, T13S/R14E (L. W. Douglas). 1958 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Pima County well logs, T13-5S/R15E (Castle Rock Ranch). 1959 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Pima County well logs, T13-15S/R15E, Maps. (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Pima County well logs, T13S/R14-15E (Wilmot/West Grant). 1946-1960 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Pima County well logs, T14, 17S/R6,8E (U.S. Indian Service). 1919- (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Pima County well logs, T15S/R2,7,8E (Sells area). (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Pima County well logs, T15S/R14E (Geophysivcsl logs). 1964 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Pima County well logs, T16S/R15E (So. Arizona International Livestock Assn.). 1966 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Pima County well logs, T16S/R14E (Clark Farm). 1964 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Pima County well logs, T17,21S/R8,10E (near Tucson). 1923 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Pima County well logs, T19S/R15E (Santa Rita Range Reserve). 1921- (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Pima County well logs, T19S/R1W (Comoti). 1922 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Pinal County well logs, Casa Grande Valley. 1936 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Pinal County well logs, not located. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Pinal County well logs, well mesasurements report. 1947 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Pinal County well logs, T3-4S/R8,9E (Magma area). 1942- (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Pinal County well logs, T4S/R3-16E. 1913 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Pinal County well logs, T5S/R2-4E. 1917 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Pinal County well logs, T5S/R5-7E. 1915- (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Pinal County well logs, T5S/R8-9E. 1912- (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Pinal County well logs, T5S/R10,12,15,20-21E. 1924- (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Pinal County well logs, T6S/R2,5E. 1911-1915 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Pinal County well logs, T6S/R6E. 1925 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Pinal County well logs, T6S/R7E0. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Pinal County well logs, T6S/R8E. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Pinal County well logs, T7S/R4-5E. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Pinal County well logs, T7S/R6E. 1915- (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Pinal County well logs, T7S/R7E. 1915- (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Pinal County well logs, T7S/R8E. 1914- (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Pinal County well logs, T7S/R14-16E. 1950 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Pinal County well logs, T8S/R6E. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Pinal County well logs, T8S/R7E. 1915 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Pinal County well logs, T8S/R8E. 1916 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Pinal County well logs, T8S/R13-18E. 1936 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Pinal County well logs, T9S/R6-7E. 1936 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Pinal County well logs, T9S/R14-19E 1909 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Pinal County well logs, T10S/R6-7E. 1937 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Pinal County well logs, T10S/R15-16E. 1940 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Mojave County well logs, T24N/R14W (Kingman). 1914 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Navajo County well logs, T11-15N/R20-23E (Joseph City). 1912- (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Yavapai County well logs, T10-13N/R3-6W. 1913 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Yuma County well logs, not located. 1917-1918 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Yuma County well logs, Wellton Mesa. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Yuma County well logs, T5-7S/R11-21W. 1926 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Yuma County well logs, T8S/R13-15W. 1925- (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Yuma County well logs, T8S/R16W 1927- (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Yuma County well logs, T8S/R17W (Mohawk Municipal Water District). 1947 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Yuma County well logs, T8S/R18W. 1923 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Yuma County well logs, T8S/R19-23W. 1920 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Yuma County well logs, T9S/R16-18W. 1916 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Yuma County well logs, T9S/R19-24W. 1921 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Yuma County well logs, T10S/R2324W (Yuma Mesa). 1922 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Yuma County well logs, T3N/R11-20W (Parker). 1916 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, Gila River. 1908 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, Hopi. 1910-1921 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, Navajo. 1910-1923 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, Navajo. 1910-1923 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, Papago. 1919-1936 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, San Carlos. 1916 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, San Carlos. 1934 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Indian Reservation well logs, San Carlos. 1934 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Railroad logs, EP & SW Railway. 1916 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Railroad logs, Santa Fe Railroad. 1910- (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Railroad logs, Santa Fe Railroad. 1910 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Railroad logs, Southern Pacific Railroad. 1882-1918 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Railroad logs, Southern Pacific Railroad (Globe to Bowie). 1928 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Out of State logs, Baja, California. 1925 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Out of State logs, California (Winterhaven area). 1929, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Out of State logs, New Mexico (Albuquerque). 1933 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Out of State logs, New Mexico (Rodeo). 1920 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Series XXIV: Water resource projects, 1919-
    Over the years, the Department has contributed expertise, through numerous studies and reports, on irrigation projects throughout the state. During the struggle for control of Colorado River waters, the Department rendered service to the state by analyzing the complex, interrelated physical and political factor, then interpreted to the legislators and to the people through bulletins and papers. The series includes much of this material.
    - General, Dams and reservoirs in Arizona. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - General, Irrigable lands classification. 1942 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - General, Irrigation and water supply papers and reports. 1953 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - General, Miscellaneous projects by R. J. Shaw. 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Irrigation projects, Beardsley Project (Maricopa water district #1). 1944 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Irrigation projects, Buttes Dam, Calculations, notes. 1947 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Irrigation projects, Buttes Dam, Clippings, studies, reports. 1946 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Irrigation projects, California Gulch survey. 1946 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Irrigation projects, Cochise County water supply and irrigation. 1919 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Colorado River Project, Controversy pamphlets. 1927-1929 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Colorado River Project, Correspondence: G.E.P. Smith and Carl Hayden. 1944-1945 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Colorado River Project, Correspondence: G.E.P. Smith and A.E. Moritz. 1945 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Colorado River Project, Correspondence: G.E.P. Smith and O.C. Williams. 1944 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Colorado River Project, Future of Irrigation in Arizona, report. 1945 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Colorado River Project, Glen Canyon Dam criteria. 1957 (Box 31, Folder 15)